Hi everyone and welcome back to our listening
course.
In this lesson we're going to practice the
last question type in IELTS listening test, which
is note completion.
This type is quite familiar to students because
it's similar to the task of taking notes on
the teacher's lecture.
The steps to handle this question type are
quite similar to those of form filling.
The only challenge for you is that you
have to listen to difficult topics, so today
we're going to learn how to deal with them.
In this lesson we are going to learn
about the note completion question type in IELTS
listening, master effective steps to answer note completion
questions accurately, identify common mistakes such as spelling
errors, exceeding word limits, misusing singular and plural
forms, and missing key distractors.
And last, apply these steps and strategies to
boost your performance through topic-specific vocabulary building,
prediction techniques, and active listening skills practice.
By the end of this lesson you'll feel
more confident to tackle note completion questions.
So let's get started.
In this part we're going to look at
requirements of note completion.
This question type often appears in section 4
of the listening test and has 10 questions.
It's often a presentation by a professor on
an academic topic.
Like in a classroom setting, you will need
to take notes of the main ideas.
This question type assesses your listening comprehension to
find specific information.
Please read the requirement carefully because it will
help you know how many words should be filled
in each blank.
Spelling of a word is really important, so
try not to make any spelling mistakes and
lose points.
The recording will be played once only, so
you should stay focused while listening.
The most important thing is when listening to
the professor's lecture on an academic topic, if
you don't have a certain vocabulary you won't
be able to understand despite having all the
tips or tricks.
So try to practice listening to a wide
range of topics so that you can improve
your ability to use the language.
In the second part of the lesson we're
going to look at the steps for note
completion questions.
They are quite similar to those of form
filling in section 1.
The first step is to read the requirement
to identify the word.
The second step is to read the title
to understand the topic of the recording.
This will help you remember topic related words.
In step 3 you have to read the
questions and underline the keywords.
These keywords can help you locate which part
speakers are talking about.
In step 4 you have to predict what
type of information is missing from each blank
and predict distractors so that you can be more
careful while listening.
Usually you will catch some paraphrases of the
keywords in the recording, so it's really important
for you to practice predicting the paraphrases.
The distractors are often found in singular and
plural nouns or in numbers ending with T
or T.
If you can't predict them it's normal to get
incorrect answers.
In step 5 you have to listen and
write the answers in the blanks.
The final step is to check the answers.
Students often skip the step and then make
unnecessary mistakes.
Sometimes it takes you just 30 seconds to check
your answer.
By doing that you can increase the number
of correct answers and remember to verify whether
the answers match the predictions.